hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
microkowski and if we haven't met yet I
help coaches and trainers use the tools
on the internet offers ads business
strategy to get more clients and to make
more money so they can make six figures
and even seven figures online now today
I have an incredible guest her name is
Ray Jenkins she has the the Superwoman
Academy and she helps women who have
experienced traumatic heartbreak heal
their soul turn their pain into Power
even if they feel guilty taking care of
themselves how to take back control of
their life even if it feels impossible
and become a superwoman because that's
who they are Ray welcome to the podcast
how are you doing today Superwoman
I am yet alive there you go awesome
pain into Power yes
tell me a little bit about how you got
into what you're doing you're a
relationship coach you you coach women
specifically your niches women and we
have we have a lot of women who listen
to this we also have a lot of men and if
you're a man listening to this I would
recommend you not discredit listening to
a podcast that has a woman coach
honestly if you want to know
how to work with women how to love women
you need to listen to women so there we
go
[Laughter]
all right so tell me how you got into
this
hey
oh
I was rejected abandoned and abused as a
child wow rejected and abandoned by both
my mom and dad I was abused by the
people that were left in charge of me
and
um
as a direct result of that I pretty much
ruined every relationship that I was
involved in
because I was so guarded I was so
non-trusting and I was unconsciously
controlling very demanding because I
needed things to be a certain way so
that I felt safe and so that I knew that
I was heard and
um I went through a um
a change I call it my my midlife crisis
when my dad passed away and it forced me
to um address a lot of the stuff that
was tucked you know I call it tucked all
those things that were tucked they came
to the surface I didn't have no control
over it they came to the surface and
everybody was like who are you like who
is this where'd you come from like
where's Ray Jenkins you that kind of
thing and as a result of me doing the
work
I had to go back and uh repair
pretty much all of those relationships
and that's when you know because I
learned how to relate to people and when
I talk to people and tell them I'm a
relationship coach I immediately say and
it's not just about how to get a man
like no it's how to love on yourself
relate to yourself know yourself so you
can relate to others and that's how I
got into it I love that I love I love
what you you stand for and all that and
and your story is is powerful I think
there's a lot of listeners on here
actually can relate with your story
um and and I got a question for you you
know you you help women Take Back
Control of their life so explain how you
were somebody who is like controlling
how somebody can go from being
controlling to taking back control of
their life because those are not the
same thing they're not the same thing
and that's where it started because I
had to realize that there's a difference
between taking in control and being
controlling taking control is so much
more effective and it works in
relationships being controlling not so
much
so explain a little bit like how
somebody could take control in a in a
relationship you know I see you guys
hear her money her man her God her mini
me her her family herself instead of it
being about other people
yeah so how you I think the practical
way of doing that or should I say the
most simplified and it might sound
oversimplified to some people but that's
where coaching comes in
save this plug oh
the sensor is taking ownership
once you understand
you your role and that you are allowing
certain things in your life so I said
that I was abused in this handle
mistreated as a child right
I brought down that mindset those
feelings their trauma into my teen years
into my young adult years into my adult
years at some point it can't be about
them anymore it has to be about me and I
realized I had to take control of my
life and it started with me only I'll
give you a perfect example my daughter's
father
man so this cat
asked me to have my daughter he came to
me this is one of my dumb broad days
okay he comes to me and says Ray we
should have a baby
and my dumb self was like okay
[Laughter]
goes away right and so
I can't I'm angry I'm angry and I'm
feeling some kind of way and then one
day it hits me like this man did nothing
to you that you didn't allow him to do
because once he did it once once he did
it twice once he did it three times you
know this is a pattern a lifestyle this
is how he is regardless of what he's
saying this is who he is this is how he
is
and I had to forgive him because I had
if I had taken and taken ownership
should I say I realized girl he only did
what you let him do and that's the
ownership taking ownership
yeah
you know and I want to ask you this
um
there's a lot of women who have been in
your position
and I'm just going to ask you what a lot
of them might be thinking are you saying
that they brought it on themselves and
that they made themselves get abused and
that they deserved it I don't think
that's about yourself yeah yeah I didn't
think that's what you're saying
no what I'm literally saying
so here's the thing the type of women
that I work with they've got tough skin
so they can handle my craftsness and my
bluntness and my upfrontness and you
know the other women yeah they'd be like
oh she didn't have to yes I did because
that's my personality and that's how I
roll so I said what I said
like no just kidding no I'm not saying
that it's your fault I'm not saying that
you asked for it I'm not saying that you
wanted it what I am saying is you
allowed it because you didn't stop it
you didn't walk away for whatever reason
and that's why I'm not blaming you like
there's no guilt there's no shame
there's no condemning you for it not
walking away I didn't have the power to
walk away he walked away from me him and
a couple other people too
who just treated me so badly but what I
understood in relationships was to be
treated badly to be mishandled to be
mistreated and that's every relationship
I got into with the dude that's the type
of relationship that I had
and you know no matter how much I barked
and no matter how tough I was he was
doing what he wanted to do how he wanted
to do a treating me the way he was and I
was I stayed because I didn't have the
strength I didn't have the power to walk
away and oh my God oh my gosh okay so I
gotta rate one for you Jeremiah I can't
this is a great one
so the one that started transformation
for me was the one that helped me
realize that I didn't have the power so
there was this dude I was so in love
with this dude Jeremiah okay
he was not in love with me all right but
I was so in love with this dude
and we were talking on the phone one day
and he says to me yes so
um we me you and your um and your best
friend we should do a threesome
it's like what
and I cussed him out
I was like you know so don't ever talk
to me like that so remember I said the
toughness and all of that or whatever
but after we got off of the phone
he you know the the conversation
eventually ended and when we got off of
the phone
I realized I asked myself
why didn't you get off the phone when he
said that why didn't you disconnect when
he said that because you felt so
disrespected you felt so like minimal
y'all like you felt so smart he made you
feel so small and you stayed there and
it was in that moment that I prayed I
said God
I don't have the power to walk away from
this man
and that was the moment that
transformation started changed started
for me with relationships and taking
ownership began so again no I'm not
judging anyone I'm talking from
experience and I know what it takes to
get free I know what it takes to stay
free I know what it takes to walk free
and it may be a hard thing to hear but
we have to take ownership without it no
one does the work
you know I want to ask you was was those
relationships a
a version of
how you grew up
absolutely absolutely exactly the same
pattern of how you grew up in those
relationships absolutely absolutely and
but clearly I didn't know it then like
you know right it was just felt normal
yeah it felt normal to have someone talk
to me any kind of way treat me any kind
of way make me last and all those kind
of things it just felt normal even
though I didn't like it it just felt
like you know when people would be like
why are you dealing with that and I'd be
like right what you mean
but you know because to me it was normal
which is so crazy right so familiar
exactly it was familiar exactly
and it's funny what you're sharing with
me I almost feel like you're talking to
me and my story and I even think some
people who are listening to this right
now can resonate in their own story you
know it wasn't relationships with with
women but it was friendships I was
getting into toxic friendships with guys
I'm just going to share a little bit of
a story right here of myself these these
these guys because I was trying to get
the approval of my dad
and I was going these toxic guys that
they would take advantage of me they
would use me for money and they would
manipulate things and then they would
threaten me
and they were abusive verbally mentally
and and and I got into these friends and
I thought that that's what friendship
was I just thought that that's what all
friendship was because that's what I saw
friendships that my parents had and
friendships that I had growing up and I
was repeating the pattern I didn't even
realize that wow I'm literally hanging
out with some some like like I I try not
to be judgmental but they were not good
people
they were not good people and I'll say
it for you they were yeah
totally exactly and so
when I realized okay I'm the one putting
myself in these situations with these
people
I'm the one that's creating these
situations and I'm responsible to get
out of it and I don't know how to it's
that's what I'm saying exactly what
you're saying I think resonates with a
lot of people I say this all the time if
you're a coach if you're a trainer you
need to work on yourself more than you
try to work on your clients
that's the first thing the second thing
is you need to watch what environment
you're in and so if you're somebody
right now who's listening to this right
now and you're in an environment that is
not healthy that you're not liking if
you are constantly anxious angry and
upset about the people that you hang out
with every single day that's a good
indicator that maybe they're not very
healthy people for you and that's no
judgment on the people listening to this
by the way because I don't want people
to feel guilty that they're doing those
things either you know and talk about
that a little bit I think a lot of
people a feel like okay I can't get out
of these situations I'm locked into it
and then they also feel guilty that they
got themselves into it talk to those two
things if you could just share a little
bit how did you eventually start to to
change your life and realize that you
could get out of these situations
that's an awesome awesome question
um when I got involved with uh network
marketing so like 20 years ago uh one of
the common themes uh will common sayings
was that you've gotta your why has to be
big enough right
and what kept me alive until I knew my
worth was my daughter
and so I didn't think that I was worth
almost anything oh I wanted valuable
stuff but I didn't think that I was
worthy or deserving of it but I did
think that she was
and that's what was my anchor because I
had to continue to become the best
version of myself
for her to see
so I wasn't doing it for me at first at
first and sometimes it takes that it
takes it being about someone else so I
tell people all the time that my
coaching stay away from those dangerous
cliches you know when people tell you
some stuff like oh it ain't about nobody
else it's all about you it can't always
be about you sometimes it needs to be
about somebody else sometimes being that
other person that will change it like
that will save your life and my daughter
was so good The Wind Beneath My Wings
because the times the impact
of all of those uh broken and abusive
relationships that I was in
um and not only just with men and
friendships family
all of it right in business all of it
because I've been an entrepreneur for
over 20 years and it was just like
wherever you go there you are okay so
I'm all the relationships no matter what
type of relationship it was I was the
common denominator okay and what I
brought with me
was filtered into those relationships
it's ripped into it poured into those
relationships and so as a result of her
I mean I mean should I say as a result
of the impact of all the devastation and
the disappointment and
the stuff that was meant to destroy me
I wanted to ball up in the knot and just
die I just wanted to ball up in the knot
and die but I would think like
if if it's hard for you imagine what it
would be like for this little girl if
you left her here she will go through
the same exact things you went through
and it would just help me refocus it
would help me refocus and keep skin in
the game it would keep me in the game
and that's and and that was it that was
it for me it had to be about somebody
else and now those of you who oh okay so
the flip side of that is God kept
dealing with me about my worth and my
value there you go and and over time he
really encouraged me that you know the
same way that you want this good for her
and you do this good for her uh yeah I'm
not there for you I I'm like who me
oh that's so good
[Music]
yes
we want the good we pray for the good
but we can't handle the good we can't
expect the good and we can't receive the
good when we're still damaged
we are still in that space of not taking
ownership but once we start doing the
work it puts us in a position where we
can start being in a state of
expectation because the word says that
um is fake you know it's faith God
responds to our faith right
um even you know Jesus is my dude okay
so even Jesus said like be unto you
according to your faith well Faith
includes expectation if you're not in a
state of expectation
you're hoping and you're wishing and
it's not likely that you're going to get
what it is that you prayed for yet
because God will continue to work on you
he continued to work on me that's what
he did so he continued to work on me and
get me into that place where I was able
to expect I was able to receive and that
is the biggest biggest thing a lot of
times we're praying for we're asking for
these things and it's not that God is
saying no he's saying okay let me get
you ready for that wow because if you
got it I want you to have it if you have
it you got to maintain it you know like
if you've got a if God blesses you with
that house if you don't keep the house
clean which is maintaining it right then
you'll have a rodent problem you're
going to have a vice problem a roach
problem I'm from the hood so you know we
had roaches I don't know about it
nowhere else but we have roaches so but
you know or your house is going to smell
bad you know those kind of things that's
the maintaining so when God gives you
the good that you be that you're
expecting that you're praying for that
you're believing for that you're able to
receive once you get it you got to
maintain it and if you can't maintain it
then the enemy of your good is just
going to rob you up and take it from you
and you won't blame God for it you're
gonna go around the same Mountain over
and over again and say why why is this
keep happening to me a lot of people say
that why does this keep happening to me
ask me how I know yeah exactly
that's so good that's so good I love I
just I love everything that you were
saying it really hit me about that like
what God thinks about us and I and I and
I discovered this past year you know
self-esteem what we believe in ourselves
and really it comes from what God thinks
about us you know as a Christian that's
where I I get it from but even if we
want to just just believing in ourselves
affects our business our relationships
see I actually used to think that it was
selfish to believe good things about
myself that it was that it was a toxic
thing for me to think that I'm a great
person uh and that came from some really
bad Bible teaching I had I grew up it
was called worm theology that taught me
in the church that that uh I need to see
myself as lower than dirt and that is so
not true that is so like like God sees
all of us as amazing incredible great
beautiful wonderful children that he's
created and that he wants to give good
gifts to that he disciplines to when
we're not you know in the right place
that he says maybe you're not ready yet
for this I'm gonna I'm gonna hold out
because I love you you you know it's all
it's kind of like if you gave a car to a
five-year-old they're gonna crash the
car
going to five-year-old wants the car
they know they're gonna have the car 10
years from now but they're not ready yet
they're not ready yet that's exactly how
it goes in our lives and so I want to
encourage those that are watching this
if you know a you got a calling
that God has
plans for your life and a Destiny and
he's given you a vision of where you're
going stay faithful to the process don't
give up because you don't see it right
now in front of you
if you hear anything from Ray and I
today
God thinks that you're amazing he thinks
they're amazing
and when you step into that when you
start to see that when you start living
like
the creator of the universe thinks that
you're amazing Everything Changes
great thanks
enjoyable you know amen and I'll be uh
completely transparent with you I am
currently
dealing with my biggest Relationship
Challenge this is a relationship with my
mother yeah and you know God is doing
something here and it's very very
challenging because I told you I want to
say what happened right
and oops one second the video popped off
it's okay okay there we go here we go
all right sorry about that we're so it's
um
It's like because my mother she has a
mental health issues and it's kind of
like okay God how do I separate her
mental defect from her Humanity because
her whole life she's been having people
handle her because listen in the black
community we didn't do
psychiatrists and psychotherapists and
you know things like that whatever and
so people who were were they deemed
crazy they would just you know they
would laugh that they were scoring you
know treated like lepers so to speak and
I realized that there had been her
experience pretty much most of her life
and it was just kind of like
okay yeah like and you know how do I
balance this because a lot of the things
that she does makes me so angry because
they're so selfish and self-serving when
I'm like I'm I'm here to serve and I'm
here to help and it's just like you know
okay you're violating me you're
disrespecting me you're mishandling me
you're mistreating me but I'm loving on
you and it makes me angry and so I'm
praying and I'm like okay God
rejection and abandonment is a common
theme I don't want to do that to her
like how do I work through this how do I
focus on her humanity and deal with that
and break through this so y'all pray for
me
you're gonna get through it you're gonna
get through it I promise you that you
know I've seen God restore the hardest
of relationships and and he'll give you
wisdom God if you're watching this as
well listeners like and you're having
trouble in relationships that's what
life is like like here can let's be real
for a second relationship like this idea
that all of our relationships and every
are perfect and that there's this
perfect little box that they all fit
into and and it all goes how we want my
friends that is that is a fantasy that
is that is Disneyland and it's never
gonna be reality on planet Earth
relationships are messy
they're messy they're hard
but I've seen God restore the hardest
relationships and so I just want to
encourage anybody who's listening to
this again the theme on this the way to
take control of your life your business
is to take ownership of okay what can I
do
how can I grow
you know what pattern am I replaying
every single day in my life
this has helped me with my relationship
with my wife with with with my mom with
with my friends I have thriving
relationships whereas four four or five
years ago I can just tell you I had
some not so good relationships in the
last four years
that has completely been a 180. in that
you know one of the biggest things
that's helped me is I even started
seeing a therapist myself I used a
betterhelp.com and started diving into
some of the deep issues that were that
were holding me back the patterns and
stuff like that and I and I grew up
where in in our church that therapy is
for the crazy people almost the same
thing that like what you were saying and
and I almost I rejected it I knew I
needed to go get some help you know you
get help if you got a broken arm why not
get help if you you got some issues with
your brain
oh my gosh yes so that is the thing and
that's what I talk about like how
because our mental health and our
emotional health is not visible we tend
to try to tuck everything but it's just
like if people saw that you broke your
toe they saw that you broke your leg and
you're walking with lips yeah they
expect you to be sitting down somewhere
with your foot propped up your leg
propped up right but because you're
mentally or emotionally broken people
are like oh you're okay no I'm not
it's okay to not be okay it's okay to
not be okay and that's where heal your
soul comes from yeah because God will
renew our spirit but we still got to
heal our soul so that our souls can
align with our spirit wow otherwise
they're in complete conflict with each
other constant conflict with each other
and hence again we're not in a spade of
space of expectation and we're not in a
space of receiving but then we're gonna
blame God and say oh God didn't come
through oh God didn't answer it oh God
must didn't want it for me and all those
other cliches the the craziness that
they teach us in the church that's
another story free yeah but something
that you said about relationships being
messy is so true because
um my daughter
um she's a whole grown adult now and uh
we we're absolute besties and everywhere
we go people will be like oh my God I
love your relationship and I'm I'm like
okay yay but I tell people when you know
when we're in conversations like listen
I'm 50. my daughter's 30. we've got a
20-year difference do you really think
that she don't get on my nerves and then
I don't get on her nerves we get off
each other totally still have a
wonderful relationship because it's
based on respect we respect each other
we love each other we respect each other
we honor each other we value each other
we appreciate each other and again it
starts with self because if you're not
that then you can't command it from
anyone else that's so good I love that
Ray you're doing some amazing things I'm
so proud of you too since I've gotten to
know you I've seen so much so much
growth so much stuff that you're doing
in your business we uh we we did some
coaching for the past couple of years
and and I just wanted to ask you too you
know if there's if there's anybody who
is a coach they're listening to this you
know what would you say to them as far
as about getting plugged in with with
working with me and stuff like that as
well what would you recommend them do
oh my gosh I'm so glad you asked me that
question
listen listen listen
here's What's So Dope about Jeremiah
he's got content he's got YouTube he's
got courses he's got all this stuff out
here for free but
if you want to if the the free is
excellent because anything that he
coaches you on pretty much will be based
on the free but here's the thing he's
going to take you by your hand and
connect the dots for you that is the
value that's the value can I tell y'all
how listen I'm a person I need
strategies and steps every time him and
I would do our our sessions he would be
like okay so what do you need out of
this I need a uh my next step I need I
need somebody to tell me what to do
because even though I know what to do I
need to hear it so that the dots are
connected and that I'm held accountable
because I've got add to the 1000th power
and listen my creativity would be like
oh we'll try this and try that what they
look like
yes oh
wait a minute and yes so absolutely
listen my Concepts about business have
changed so much I've always had this
posture but my business savvy like and
I've had business savvy too but this
online work that let me be very clear
about that this online world
be connected with Jeremiah has changed
my experience I was drowning y'all I was
so drowning but every time we came to
the call
um we it was just like he pointed me in
another Direction he told me to take
this step to keep going take the step
and keep going so does he know his stuff
absolutely so what would I encourage you
to do work with him duh like that's
awesome and I'd say if there's any any
women that are listening to this they
need to check you out over at I support
superwomen.com I'll put the link in the
podcast and what do you help
specifically like women do in in your
program and your coaching what what are
some of the resources that they can get
from you
oh my gosh so I've got quite a few uh
resources that are free I had the um the
the strong woman uh personality quiz
which is an assessment that helps you to
understand yourself understand why you
can't walk away sometimes like what's
hardwired about you what's part of your
personality that's who you are and what
are parts of your personality you know
parts of your personality that are not
really your personality those kind of
things you just think they're your
personality
um I've got the uh the mini course for
relationships I've got
um many mindset courses
um uh money mindset courses I've got all
kinds of stuff I've even started a group
for uh the Superwoman as well to come in
and it's brand new but um come in so we
can get some engagement popping up in
there y'all very cool
that's awesome I love that listen thank
you for being on here thank you for
opening up thank you for sharing your
journey with people you know a lot of
people listen to this like your courage
today is inspiring to them you know they
they see you I promise on this podcast
and say I want to be where Ray Jenkins
is today I know I have a number of
listeners that they're going to be
inspired by that and you know what I'm
gonna I'm gonna recommend a number of
women to come to come your way who've
been through a similar journey I have a
lot of them that follow me and I just
don't really have much resource for them
because I'm not I never been through
their journey and that's not what I
specialize in but I think now I know
where to send them
y'all plug in with her she is a rock
star she is amazing she is helping
change lives thank you for being here
thank you for having me yeah yeah Hey
listen if this podcast episode has
helped you in any way share it with some
people people don't just listen to it
and then go on your way I think this is
going to help other people as well
that's the only thing I ask
grow your life everybody and we'll talk
soon have a good one